Vitaly Kravchenko

📠 LinkedIn │ 🖡 +7-777-655-9993 │ 🤀 dearvito.github.io │ 🞽 vitaly.kravchenko@yahoo.com │ 🖓 GitHub

About me

Besides the usual Java developer knowledge, I have experience with Dragon-JAVA language, used to develop and test onboard software for spacecraft. Created and taught a Backend development course at my university. It is really important for me to actively communicate with my team, making decisions that allow building an awesome product. I dedicate myself to my work and can't imagine another way of life.

Skills

- Java | Spring Framework | Hibernate | JPA | JDBC | SQL | MySQL | PostgreSQL | Docker | Docker-compose | Maven | Gradle
- OOP | Git | REST API | JSON | HTTP | HTML | XML | Javascript | Apache Tomcat | Atlassian Trello | Jenkins CI/CD | Swagger
- Linux | Lombok | JUnit | Mockito | Unit Testing | Integration Testing | Microservices | Backend | English, Kazakh, Russian

Experience _

Java Developer

Upiter Global Systems

Almaty, Kazakhstan 08/2021 - 10/2022

- Java-based core functionality development, integrations, new architecture implementation, application functionality extension on microservices architecture.
- Applied application-specific technical skills to independently create deliverables (e.g., specifications, program changes, unit testing scripts, documentation, etc.). Maintaining applications, fixing bugs, implementing new features. Participate in application development from scratch to production environment.
- Conducting an audit and suggesting ideas for improvement.

Java Developer

Asia Soft

Astana, Kazakhstan 10/2020 - 08/2021

- Development of Java-based software for intelligent data analysis platform based on microservice architecture.
- Optimization and refactoring of existing systems to improve performance, optimize resources, etc.
- Fixing bugs, implementing new features, finding problems in the production environment.
- Testing programming code and applications.

Education _____

Master of Science

Moscow Aviation Institute

Baikonur, Kazakhstan 09/2010 - 08/2016

Major in Spacecraft software development and testing

Mentorship_

- Java Mentor: mentoring and giving career advice to students (06/2022 Present)
- Computer Science Tutor: Java Programming | Data Structure and Algorithms | coding interview prep

Others

- From 2013 to 2020 (7 years), I worked for Roscosmos State Corporation as an engineer and was involved in the development, debugging of software and ground control system computers, as well as testing programs in the Dragon-JAVA language.
- Key accomplishments:
 - Improved the efficiency of the temperature control system (refinement resulted in a 14-19% reduction in power
 - Reduced probability of error due to human factors (made changes to a number of test instructions, eliminated errors/inaccuracies).